thehealthy.com 2019-12-25

# Privacy Policy - TMB

### Effective as of November 7, 2017

##### Updated as of December 20, 2019

California residents have additional rights explained [here](https://www.trustedmediabrands.com/ca-privacy-notice/) under California’s Shine the Light law and, effective January 1, 2020, the California Consumer Privacy Act.

This Privacy Policy is applicable to any website, mobile app and other online service originating in the United States and owned and operated by Trusted Media Brands, Inc. or any of its U.S. subsidiaries and/or affiliates under its control (collectively the “Company”, “we”, “us” or “our”) that states it is governed by this Privacy Policy and/or links to this Privacy Policy as well as to consumer information that we receive from you or a third party in connection with Company publications and other products and services we offer to you (including both offline and online orders of subscriptions to Company magazines and other products and services we offer to consumers) unless otherwise specified (collectively, the “Service”). Subsidiaries and affiliates of Trusted Media Brands, Inc. include, without limitation, RDA Enthusiast Brands, LLC and Home Service Publications, Inc. As of March 24, 2019, the Company currently owns and operates the Service for the following brands (our “Family of Publications”):

  * Best Health U.S. ([www.besthealthus.com](http://www.besthealthus.com/))
  * Birds & Blooms ([www.birdsandblooms.com](http://www.birdsandblooms.com/))
  * Construction Pro Tips ([www.constructionprotips.com](http://www.constructionprotips.com/))
  * Country ([www.country-magazine.com](http://www.country-magazine.com/))
  * Country Woman ([www.countrywomanmagazine.com](http://www.countrywomanmagazine.com/))
  * Farm & Ranch Living ([www.farmandranchliving.com](http://www.lovethecountry.com/))
  * Haven Home Media ([www.havenhomemedia.com](http://mediakit.havenhomemedia.com/))
  * Reader’s Digest ([www.rd.com](http://www.rd.com/), [www.rdstore.com](http://www.rdstore.com/))
  * Reminisce ([www.reminisce.com](http://www.reminisce.com/))
  * Simple & Delicious ([www.tasteofhome.com/simple](https://www.tasteofhome.com/recipes/simple---delicious-magazine))
  * Taste of Home ([www.tasteofhome.com](http://www.tasteofhome.com/), [www.shoptasteofhome.com](http://www.shoptasteofhome.com/))
  * [TheHealthy.com](http://thehealthy.com/) ([www.thehealthy.com](https://www.thehealthy.com/))
  * Family Handyman ([www.familyhandyman.com](http://www.familyhandyman.com/), [www.mydiyuniversity.com](https://www.mydiyuniversity.com/), [https://insider.familyhandyman.com](https://insider.familyhandyman.com/))

Any new brands, publications, sites and services acquired by or created by the Company will also be included in our Family of Publications, unless otherwise specified. This Privacy Policy will tell you what information we collect when you visit the Service or order Company publications or other products and services we offer to you (whether you do so offline or online), how we use that information and what choices you have about how it is used. Some functions and services offered through the Service may have additional privacy statements that supplement this Privacy Policy. We urge you to read our entire Privacy Policy, and any applicable additional privacy statements, so that you will understand both our commitment to you and your privacy, and how you can participate in that commitment. Please note that unless otherwise indicated, this Privacy Policy does not cover any information that may be collected elsewhere, including without limitation through any third party website.

**Collection of Personally Identifiable Information**

Some functions and services offered through the Service require that you provide certain personally identifiable information (“PII”). We may also collect PII when, whether you do so offline or online, you order a subscription to a Company publication, order other products and services we offer to you, or furnish us with information relating to your order or account. PII that we may collect includes email address, name, postal address, telephone number, date of birth, credit card number or other account number. We may also collect other information about you that we associate with your PII such as your interests, preferences and demographics. For example, we may collect information about your interests in certain health, food and lifestyle topics. We collect this information for example, when you order a product, enter a contest or sweepstakes, request a catalog, or register for a mailing list. To the extent we combine information about your Service usage with PII, we will treat it as PII. However, to the extent we “de-identify” (i.e., removal or modification of personally identifiable elements or the extraction of non-personally identifiable elements, including through anonymization, pseudonymization and hashing) the information we do not consider it PII for purposes of this Privacy Policy and may, subject to applicable law, use and share it without limitation. We do not make any assurance that de-identified data is not capable of re-identification.

From time to time, we may make available certain applications for use on mobile or connected devices (each application, an “App”). The type of PII we collect will vary by App, but may include both precise and non-precise geolocation information for purposes such as to provide you with access to local service, offers and promotions relevant to the App (e.g., coupons for local stores). Each App may include its own privacy policy explaining how we collect PII (including geolocation information) when you use that App; if not, then this Privacy Policy will apply to the App. You should always read the applicable privacy policy before downloading the App.

Back to Table of Contents __

**Use of Personally Identifiable Information**

We may use your PII and other information we collect about you for any purposes not prohibited by applicable law or inconsistent with the applicable Privacy Policy or any statement made by us to you in writing at the time of collection.  Such uses may include, without limitation, use of your information to:

  * operate and improve the Service and our other products and services;
  * understand you and your preferences for purposes such as to enhance your experience and enjoyment using the Service, and our other products and services;
  * process and deliver promotion (e.g., contest and sweepstakes) entries, winners and rewards;
  * send you a welcoming email, to contact you about your use of the Service and to provide important Service and other updates;
  * provide the services, products or information you request and to process payments and complete any transactions in connection therewith;
  * respond to your comments and questions and provide customer service;
  * provide and deliver products and services you request;
  * request feedback and to enable us to develop, customize and improve the Service, our Family of Publications, and other products and services;
  * send you surveys or questionnaires;
  * send you newsletters, including any online newsletter(s) you have requested or, for print subscribers, those online newsletters that are editorial companion pieces (e.g. Taste of Home Subscriber Exclusive) to our print publications;
  * send you related information, including confirmations, invoices, technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages;
  * communicate with you about new contests and sweepstakes, promotions and rewards, upcoming events, and other news about products and services offered by Company and our selected partners;
  * use for editorial purposes, such as to contact you about content you have submitted to the Service or to give attribution to content you submit;
  * send an email on your behalf which contains a display or link to a recipe, article, advice or other content you have selected to share with a friend through our Email-a-Friend service (however, we do not use the name and email address you provide us through this feature for any other purpose);
  * link or combine it with other personal information we get offline and/or from third parties, for purposes such as to help understand your needs, provide you with better service, and determine whether marketing offers from third parties would be of interest to you; and
  * investigate and take action against fraudulent or illegal activity or improper conduct and otherwise protect us and our users.

Company may save your credit card information for use when you log in to make future purchases. Company may store and process PII in the United States and other countries.

Back to Table of Contents __

**Sharing of Personally Identifiable Information**

Company may share your PII for any purposes and circumstances not prohibited by applicable law or inconsistent with the applicable Privacy Policy or any statement made by us to you in writing at the time of collection, including without limitation:

  * We may share your PII with our affiliates, our technical consultants, auditors and other third parties who act on our behalf, for example, to make the Service available, enhance functionality, or provide services related to the Service or fulfillment of subscriptions or orders for any of our publications or other products and services (such as sending emails, processing credit cards, fulfilling subscriptions and other orders, providing customer service, and performing data-, information technology-, or marketing-related services), and/or who assist us in producing, delivering, billing, collecting payment for, renewing and otherwise managing content, samples, products, and gifts and prizes.
  * We may make your PII, along with certain other information about you (such as your interest in particular health or lifestyle topics or your subscription information), available to third parties for the purpose of offering products and services that may interest you, unless you opt out of such information sharing. (See the sections below entitled “ **[Notice of Your Choices about Our Use and Sharing of Personally Identifiable Information](https://www.trustedmediabrands.com/privacy-policy/#notice)** ” and “ **[Notice to California Customers – Your California Privacy Rights](https://www.trustedmediabrands.com/privacy-policy/#california)** ” on opting out of information sharing).
  * We may transfer your PII and other information in connection with or during negotiation of any merger, financing, acquisition or dissolution, transaction or proceeding involving sale, transfer, divestiture or disclosure of all or a portion of our business or assets to another company.
  * We will consider, and may release, PII to third parties: to (i) comply with laws or to respond to lawful requests and legal process, (ii) to protect the rights and property of Company, our agents, customers, members, and others, including to enforce our agreements, policies and terms of use, or (iii) in an emergency to protect the personal safety of Company employees, customers, or any person.

We may also provide aggregate statistics and de-identified data about our customers, which we treat as non-PII as permitted by applicable law, including data about traffic patterns and related site information, to third parties for their own purposes, including statistical analysis.  For instance, we and third parties may convert your PII to a unique identifier, such as through hashing (which we treat as non-PII as permitted by applicable law), and we and third parties may use and share that data as permitted by applicable law, including to match data attributes to and from other data sources.  Any such third party activities are subject to their privacy policies and practices.

Back to Table of Contents __

**Your Sharing of Personally Identifiable Information**

Please be aware that when you connect and share your actions, comments, content and information, for example, through discussion board postings on the Service, those actions are not private. Others may capture personal information you post, including your email address, and may use the data to identify or contact you, including to send you emails. We cannot control such actions by others. Please be mindful of your own privacy needs as you choose who to connect with and what to share and make public. If you share information about others, please be sure to respect their privacy and get consent for any information you may share about them. If you use our Email-a-Friend service, you represent that you have permission for the recipient to send that person the message and you accept that your name and email will be disclosed to them as part of that message.

Back to Table of Contents __

**Notice of Your Choices about Our Use and Sharing of Personally Identifiable Information**

If you do not wish to receive promotional and newsletter emails from any one of our Family of Publications you may click on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of an email.

You can also change your promotional and newsletter email preferences for all our Family of Publications and our promotion lists for receiving offers from third parties via email by [clicking here to go to the E-Mail Preference Center form](http://pages.email.rd.com/page.aspx?QS=c76003443ff9837dd7351e542c0c9ccb23ce729861533058).

If you opt out of promotional or newsletter emails from any of our Family of Publications, we may continue to send you certain communications such as service announcements and administrative messages, relating to the Company or the Service that are necessary to our relationship with you.

If you wish to opt out of our promotion lists for receiving offers via postal mail or telemarketing from third parties for their products and services, contact customer service at [customercare@rd.com](mailto:customercare@rd.com) or at:

_**Trusted Media Brands, Inc.**_  
_**PO Box  3124**_  
_**Harlan, IA 51593**_  
_**Phone #: 877-342-4775**_

You may also use the postal address above for general customer service questions.

Back to Table of Contents __

**Third Party Activities**

If you submit PII through a form on the Service to request information from an advertiser or other third party, choose to otherwise share your PII with a third party such as by sharing stories you read by connecting with social networking services, or click on a link on the Service to go to a third party site that may collect information about you, we are not responsible for the privacy practices of, including any marketing or other use of your PII by, those third parties. To learn more about any other company or organization’s privacy practices, we suggest you contact them directly about their privacy policy.

Back to Table of Contents __

**Notice to California Customers – Your California Privacy Rights**

California residents have additional rights explained [here](https://www.trustedmediabrands.com/ca-privacy-notice/) under California’s Shine the Light law and, effective January 1, 2020 the California Consumer Privacy Act.

Back to Table of Contents __

**Information for Nevada Consumers**

Nevada law requires website operators to provide a way for Nevada consumers to opt out of the sale of certain information that the website operator may collect about them. This information is limited to direct identifiers (such as your name, postal address and email address) collected by a website operator through an Internet website or online service and maintained by the operator in an accessible form. When Nevada consumers opt out of the sale of their covered information, website operators must ensure that information is not sold to another business that will further license or sell the information to others.

If you are a Nevada resident and you would like to opt out of the sale of your covered information, please complete this [Opt-out Form](https://www.trustedmediabrands.com/opt-out-form/). Note that this form requires your full name, street address, city, zip code, and email address if you have one. We will send any correspondence concerning your request to you at the email address you provided (if you have an email address) or your street address (if you do not have an email address). We will not accept requests submitted via other means (such as telephone, postal mail, or email), and we are not responsible for any forms that do not have complete information or are not properly sent.

Back to Table of Contents __

**Third Party Advertising and Analytics**

We may also use third parties to serve ads on the Service. Certain third parties may automatically collect information about your visits to this and other websites, your IP address, your ISP, the browser you use to visit the Service (but not your name, address, email address or telephone number), unless hashed or otherwise converted to non-PII. They do this by using cookies, clear gifs or other Tracking Technologies (defined below). Information collected may be used, among other things, to deliver advertising targeted to your interests and to better understand the usage and visitation of the Service and the other sites and services tracked by these third parties (“Interest-based Advertising”). We are not responsible for Tracking Technologies in or related to third party ads, and we encourage you to check the privacy policies of advertisers and/or ad services to learn about their use of cookies and other technology.

You may choose whether to receive some Interest-based Advertising by submitting opt-outs. One of the third party ad servers that delivers Interest-based Advertising to you is Doubleclick. For Doubleclick’s Privacy Policy, [click here](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/). Some of the other advertisers and service providers that perform advertising-related services for us and third parties may participate in the Digital Advertising Alliance’s (“DAA”) Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising. To learn more about how you can exercise certain choices regarding Interest-based Advertising, visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>, and <http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices> for information on the DAA’s opt-out program for mobile apps.  Some of these companies may also be members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”). To learn more about the NAI and your opt-out options for their members, see [http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/](https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/). Please be aware that, even if you are able to opt out of certain kinds of Interest-based Advertising, you may continue to receive other types of ads.  Opting out only means that those selected members should no longer deliver certain Interest-based Advertising to you, but does not mean you will no longer receive any targeted content and/or ads ( _e.g._ , from other ad networks). Also, if your browsers are configured to reject cookies when you visit these opt-out webpages, or you subsequently erase your cookies, use a different device or web browsers or use a non-browser-based method of access ( _e.g._ , mobile app), your NAI / DAA browser-based opt-out may not, or may no longer, be effective.  We support the ad industry’s  **2009 Self-regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising**  (<https://www.iab.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/ven-principles-07-01-09.pdf> _)_  and expect that ad networks Company directly engages to serve you Interest-based Advertising will do so as well, though we cannot guaranty their compliance.  We are not responsible for effectiveness of, or compliance with, any third-parties’ opt-out options or programs or the accuracy of their statements regarding their programs.

Company may use Google Analytics, Adobe Analytics or other service providers for analytics services.  These analytics services may use cookies and other Tracking Technologies to help us analyze Service users and how they use the Service.  Information generated by these services ( _e.g._ , your IP address and other usage information) may be transmitted to and stored by these service providers on servers in the U.S. (or elsewhere) and these service providers may use this information for purposes such as evaluating your use of the Service, compiling statistic reports on the Service’s activity, and providing other services relating to Service activity and other Internet usage. You may exercise choices regarding the use of cookies from Google Analytics by going to <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout> or downloading the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on. You may exercise choices regarding the use of cookies from Adobe Analytics by going to [http://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html](https://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html) under the section labeled “Tell our customers not to measure your use of their websites or tailor their online ads for you.”

Back to Table of Contents __

**Company Ads on Third Party Sites**

We may use information collected using Tracking Technologies on our Service and in our emails to deliver Company advertising displayed to you on third party sites. We also may use Tracking Technologies information to know when you return to the Service after visiting these third party sites or when you go to a third party site or service after visiting the Service.  We may use this information and other information about you, for purposes such as to try to understand your interests and show you relevant Company advertising about products and services you may need. For more information about your choices regarding some of these types of uses of Tracking Technologies, please go to <http://www.aboutads.info/choices> and see the prior section above.

Back to Table of Contents __

**Cookies, Web Beacons and Server Logs**

Company, and third parties such as related Web hosting providers, and advertisers and ad serving and tracking companies, sometimes utilize “cookie” technology and other tracking technologies now and hereafter developed (“Tracking Technologies”) on or in connection with the Service. Cookies are bits of data stored on your hard drive that contain no personally identifying information (but may associate a unique identifier with your device and/or collect information that is hashed or otherwise converted to non-PII). Not all Web browsers accept cookies, and those that do usually provide a preference or setting that allows you to refuse and remove most types of browser cookies. If your browser does not accept cookies, you may still enjoy the Service but not all features and functionality may work.

We may also use local shared objects, also known as Flash cookies, to store your preferences such as volume control for videos, or display content based upon what you view on the Service to personalize your visit. Third party partners provide certain features on the Service and may display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity, using Flash cookies to help track and store information about you. Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored. Cookie management tools provided by your browser usually will not remove Flash cookies. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for certain Flash cookies [click here](https://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118).

We and third parties may collect information using Web beacons. Web beacons are electronic images that may be used on the Service or in our emails. We may use Web beacons to deliver cookies, count visits, understand usage and campaign effectiveness, collect and share information that is hashed or otherwise converted to non-PII, and to tell if an email has been opened and acted upon.

Server logs capture certain non-personally identifying data (but do track device identifiers), such as the time and date of a Web visit or opening an email, the browser and operating system being used, and the Web URL a user linked from. This information may be used for various purposes, such as use in aggregate form to help us plan system enhancements when necessary and to provide content that is compatible with our visitors’ Web-browsing systems. We also collect information about keyword searches performed by visitors on the Service. We do not collect your name or email address as a result of using a search feature. We may keep logs of all words searched to help us learn what kinds of information Service visitors are seeking, and to improve our Service.

Your browser settings may allow you to automatically transmit a “Do Not Track” signal to online services you visit. Note, however, there is no consensus among industry participants as to what “Do Not Track” means in this context.  Like many online services, we currently do not alter our practices when the Service receives a “Do Not Track” signal from a visitor’s browser.  To find out more about “Do Not Track,” you can visit [http://www.allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/), but we are not responsible for the completeness or accuracy of this third party information. Some third parties, however, may offer you choices regarding their Tracking Technologies, such as is described above regarding analytics and Interest-based Advertising. One way to potentially identify cookies on our Service is to add the free Ghostery plug-in to your browser ([ **www.ghostery.com**](https://www.ghostery.com/)), which according to Ghostery will display for you traditional, browser-based cookies associated with the websites (but not mobile apps) you visit and privacy and opt-out policies and options of the parties operating those cookies.

Company participates in the Adobe Experience Cloud Device Co-op to better understand how you use our sites across various devices you use, and to deliver tailored promotions. Go to [https://cross-device-privacy.adobe.com](https://cross-device-privacy.adobe.com/) to learn more about how Adobe does this and to manage your choices relating to this linking of devices.

Back to Table of Contents __

**Privacy and Security Precaution Warning**

Please note that no data transmission over the Internet is 100% secure. As a result, we cannot guarantee the security of the information that you transmit via the Service.

Back to Table of Contents __

**Notice to International Visitors**

Company is based in the U.S. and the information we and our service providers collect is governed by U.S. law. If you are accessing the Service from outside of the U.S., please be aware that information collected through the Service may be transferred to, processed, stored, and used in the U.S. Data protection laws in the U.S. may be different from those of your country of residence. Your use of the Service or provision of any information therefore constitutes your consent to the transfer to and from, processing, usage, sharing, and storage of your information, including Personal Information, in the U.S. as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

Back to Table of Contents __

**Privacy Policy Changes**

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to prospectively change, modify, add, or remove portions of this policy at any time. Please bookmark this page and check it periodically. We will post any changes online.

Back to Table of Contents __

**Terms of Use**

Please also read the Terms of Use posted on each online Service to understand the additional terms and conditions which apply to use of that site or App.

Back to Table of Contents __

© 2019 TRUSTED MEDIA BRANDS, INC.
